Matthew Boddy boddym@yahoo.com 478.284.7581

Professional Summary

Ever since my family got our first computer when I was in the second grade, my love affair with technology and creativity has powered my success in school and in work. For the past three years, I have been working as a web developer and have greatly enjoyed the creative outlet that allows for writing and design. Going forward, I would like to pursue a position as a web developer that utilizes my technology, design, and writing skills.

Core Strengths

- Visual thinker
- Technical and analytical
- Natural bent for creativity

- Task and process driven
- Effective on a team or independent
- Strong work ethic, integrity driven, and reliable

Technology Snapshot: HTML, CSS, PHP, Javascript, Python, Ajax, ASP, Java, C#, C++, Wordpress, Squarespace, GIMP, MySql

Professional Experience

Technology

- Programmed in Javascript and Jquery across a wide variety of professional projects at Sleepless Media while learning new disciplines, languages, and methodologies, ultimately creating products that pleased the clients
- Programmed a wide variety of websites, apps, and algorithms as a full stack web developer at LitmusBox LLC, using several different disciplines to exceed clients' expectations
- Programmed a text-based adventure game from the dirt up using C# and researched a wide variety of subjects, including history, religion, and marine biology to create an immersive experience

Design

- Conducted QAs and implemented change orders as a full stack developer at Sleepless Media while maintaining the aesthetics and UX indicated in mock-ups and requested through client feedback
- Designed several professional websites as a full stack developer at LitmusBox LLC, paying particular attention to user experience and interface while providing an aesthetic that pleased the clients
- Programmed and implemented programs and algorithms in an aesthetically pleasing way that exceeded clients' expectations

Writing

- Wrote professional articles as a writer for Sleepless Media, including news, tutorials, and technical writing on the subject of web development and the constantly shifting world of technology in general
- Wrote professional websites as a contractor for LitmusBox LLC in several mediums on as many subjects; clients were very happy and went on to use the materials successfully
- Wrote several process flow documents at LitmusBox LLC to train clients' employees to use produced materials for support after the commission, which drew appreciation and high reviews

Employment

Web Developer, Copywriter	Sleepless Media	2018 - 2019
Associate Web Developer	LitmusBox LLC	2017 – 2018
Freelance Web Developer	Self-Employed	2015 – 2017
Research Veterinary Librarian	University of Georgia	2013 – 2015
Insurance Specialist	The Perinatal Center	2010 – 2012
Field Researcher	Doctor Paul Seale	2010 – 2011
Municipal Liaison	National Novel Writing Month	2007

Education

Bachelor of Science. Computer Science with Programming Specialization, Middle Georgia State College. Graduated, May 2015.

Master of Arts. Education with Middle School Education Specialization, Clemson University. Graduated, May 2010. Bachelor of Arts. English, Furman University. Graduated, May 2008.